FEDOR SAKHAROV

fedor.sakharov@gmail.com • tg:theo_montekki • montekki.github.io • github/montekki

ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer with background in Systems Software development, Networking, Information Security and Blockchains. For the past 4+ years I have been writing code in Rust. Currently my main interest outside of work is the field of Zero Knowledge, SNARKs.

EXPERIENCE

Core Software Developer, Parity Technologies

Dec 2018 — Present

- Worked on libp2p implementation in Rust
- Worked on the previous version of Parachain Consensus code for Polkadot
- Implemented the skeleton and several subsystems with the current Parachain Consensus
- Built a framework in Rust for massive chain integration testing in Kubernetes with rust: gurke
- Helped maintain cachepot: a caching build server
- Lead the team effort to release a new version of cold wallet parity-signer

Technologies: Rust, Networking, libp2p, Parachain Consensus, Cold Wallets, Kubernetes, CachePot Build Server, CI, CD, Load Testing,

Software Engineer, Waves Platform

Sep 2018 — Dec 2018

• Started the development of the Waves Blockchain node implementation in go: gowaves

Technologies: Go

Software Engineer, SONM

Jun 2018 — Aug 2018

Worked on the implementation of SONM: decentralized fog computing marketplace

Technologies: Go, Docker, Ethereum, Solidity, CI, CD

Senior Software Engineer; Team Lead, Positive Technologies

Oct 2015 — Jun 2018

- Implemented a high-speed traffic capture and analysis for the Application Firewall project
- Implemented various features within the in-house fork of the NGINX web server
- Lead an R&D team
- Researched topics in Blockchains and Al
- Presented Al research at DEFCON 26 in Las Vegas: youtube
- Presented research on EVM bytecode reversing at r2con: youtube

Technologies: EVM, C, NGINX, AF_PACKET, PF_RING, libnuma, PostgreSQL

Senior Software Engineer, Group-IB

Feb 2014 — Oct 2015

- Started the development of the new product with IDS/IPS capabilities
- Took the project to production
- Supervised the first production installations within the clients' ecosystems

Technologies: C, Linux Kernel, Suricata, AF_PACKET, PostgreSQL, Logstash,

Systems Software Engineer, Security Code

Feb 2012 — Feb 2014

- Developed in-house HIDS solution within Linux Kernel
- Helped with launching first versions of the in-house IDS solutions

Technologies: C, Linux Kernel, Suricata, AF_PACKET, PF_RING, Qt

Researcher, Moscow State University,

Mar 2009 — Jan 2012

• Performed Research & Develop work on different project.

EDUCATION

Moscow State University, Master of Science

2005 - 2018

- Thesis: Improving the fine-grained security control within the Linux Kernel github
- Taught a class on Haskell
- Taught Fundamentals of Information Security

•

CURRENT PROJECTS

Implementing Protocols in ZK

- The goal is to self-educate in the topics in Zero Knowledge
- Implementations of the protocols from <u>Proofs, Arguments and Zero Knowledge</u> book by Justin Thaler in Rust: blog posts

SKILLS

- · Code: Rust, C, Golang
- Tools: GH Actions, Docker, Shell, Kubernetes,